<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>WSL on See Hiong&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://seehiong.github.io/tags/wsl/</link>
    <description>Recent content in WSL on See Hiong&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 08:00:00 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://seehiong.github.io/tags/wsl/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Talos Linux: Setting Up a Secure, Immutable Kubernetes Cluster</title>
      <link>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2024/09/talos-linux-setting-up-a-secure-immutable-kubernetes-cluster/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 08:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2024/09/talos-linux-setting-up-a-secure-immutable-kubernetes-cluster/</guid>
      <description>This post guides you through setting up a secure, immutable Kubernetes cluster using Talos Linux. It covers installing Talos on control and worker nodes, configuring local storage with hostPath and Local Path Provisioner, and setting up the Kubernetes Dashboard with an admin user for cluster management. With Talos Linux, you achieve a minimal, API-managed Kubernetes environment without SSH or systemd, making it ideal for a secure and reliable homelab or production setup.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stable Diffusion: Text-to-Image Modeling Journey</title>
      <link>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2024/02/stable-diffusion-text-to-image-modeling-journey/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2024 10:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2024/02/stable-diffusion-text-to-image-modeling-journey/</guid>
      <description>This post explores Stable Diffusion, a latent text-to-image diffusion model in machine learning. Diffusion models, with forward, reverse, and sampling components, understand and generate patterns in datasets. Illustrating applications in image tasks, it introduces the process of installing and utilizing Stable Diffusion. The post details image generation and modification using prompts, with examples and troubleshooting. Notably, it shares an encounter with CUDA out-of-memory errors and the resolution through image resizing. Overall, it offers a comprehensive guide, combining theoretical insights with practical implementation steps in a professional manner.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Empowering Autogen: Enabling Seamless Java Code Execution</title>
      <link>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2023/12/empowering-autogen-enabling-seamless-java-code-execution/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 20:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2023/12/empowering-autogen-enabling-seamless-java-code-execution/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I explored enhancing Autogen&amp;rsquo;s capabilities by enabling seamless Java code execution. Drawing inspiration from 0xlws&amp;rsquo; fork supporting JavaScript, I embarked on modifying Autogen to robustly support Java. I detailed the setup process, including installing Java on Windows Subsystem for Linux (WSL) and modifying key files. The post includes code snippets showcasing the changes, recompilation steps, and instructions for generating Java code. I extended functionality to additional test cases, seamlessly switching between Java and Python code execution. Docker integration for Java code execution was also optimized, showcasing Autogen&amp;rsquo;s versatility and robust development experience.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking the Power of Machine Learning with MLC LLM</title>
      <link>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2023/09/unlocking-the-power-of-machine-learning-with-mlc-llm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Sep 2023 20:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2023/09/unlocking-the-power-of-machine-learning-with-mlc-llm/</guid>
      <description>I delve into the transformative realm of MLC LLM, an advanced universal deployment solution for extensive language models. My post guides you personally through the setup, emphasizing critical components like TVM and Conda. I demonstrate the process, including TVM installation via pip, Conda setup on WSL, and Vulkan SDK installation for optimal performance. Navigating the MLC Chat exploration, I detail creating a Conda environment and running MLC LLM&amp;rsquo;s CLI version, offering a glimpse into its potential through a sample question. With MLC LLM and MLC Chat at your fingertips, the world of machine learning and language understanding unfolds boundless possibilities. 🚀🧠</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Utilizing vLLM for Efficient Language Model Serving</title>
      <link>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2023/08/utilizing-vllm-for-efficient-language-model-serving/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 20:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2023/08/utilizing-vllm-for-efficient-language-model-serving/</guid>
      <description>Embarking on my journey with vLLM, I explore its potential for streamlined Large Language Model (LLM) inference and deployment. The blog details my personal experience setting up vLLM on a Windows Subsystem for Linux (WSL) instance running Ubuntu 22.04. I meticulously guide through installing WSL, NVIDIA GPU drivers, CUDA Toolkit, and Docker for efficient utilization. Delving into vLLM setup within the NVIDIA PyTorch Docker image, I navigate through the installation process and launch the API server. The blog provides insights into querying the model and creating a Docker image snapshot, offering a comprehensive guide to efficient language model serving.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
