<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>WSL on See Hiong&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://seehiong.github.io/tags/wsl/</link>
    <description>Recent content in WSL on See Hiong&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 08:00:00 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://seehiong.github.io/tags/wsl/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Talos Linux: Setting Up a Secure, Immutable Kubernetes Cluster</title>
      <link>https://seehiong.github.io/2024/talos-linux-setting-up-a-secure-immutable-kubernetes-cluster/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 08:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://seehiong.github.io/2024/talos-linux-setting-up-a-secure-immutable-kubernetes-cluster/</guid>
      <description>This post guides you through setting up a secure, immutable Kubernetes cluster using Talos Linux. It covers installing Talos on control and worker nodes, configuring local storage with hostPath and Local Path Provisioner, and setting up the Kubernetes Dashboard with an admin user for cluster management. With Talos Linux, you achieve a minimal, API-managed Kubernetes environment without SSH or systemd, making it ideal for a secure and reliable homelab or production setup.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stable Diffusion: Text-to-Image Modeling Journey</title>
      <link>https://seehiong.github.io/2024/stable-diffusion-text-to-image-modeling-journey/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2024 10:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://seehiong.github.io/2024/stable-diffusion-text-to-image-modeling-journey/</guid>
      <description>This post explores Stable Diffusion, a latent text-to-image diffusion model in machine learning. Diffusion models, with forward, reverse, and sampling components, understand and generate patterns in datasets. Illustrating applications in image tasks, it introduces the process of installing and utilizing Stable Diffusion. The post details image generation and modification using prompts, with examples and troubleshooting. Notably, it shares an encounter with CUDA out-of-memory errors and the resolution through image resizing. Overall, it offers a comprehensive guide, combining theoretical insights with practical implementation steps in a professional manner.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Empowering Autogen: Enabling Seamless Java Code Execution</title>
      <link>https://seehiong.github.io/archives/2023/empowering-autogen-enabling-seamless-java-code-execution/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 20:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://seehiong.github.io/archives/2023/empowering-autogen-enabling-seamless-java-code-execution/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the pursuit of enhancing Autogen&amp;rsquo;s capabilities, I drew inspiration from &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/0xlws/autogen&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;0xlws&amp;rsquo; fork&lt;/a&gt; supporting JavaScript. This led me to embark on a journey to modify Autogen, enabling robust support for Java code execution.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;setting-up&#34;&gt;Setting up&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Begin by ensuring that Java is installed on your Windows Subsystem for Linux (WSL) using the following command:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;sudo apt install openjdk-17-jdk-headless&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pr</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking the Power of Machine Learning with MLC LLM</title>
      <link>https://seehiong.github.io/archives/2023/unlocking-the-power-of-machine-learning-with-mlc-llm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Sep 2023 20:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://seehiong.github.io/archives/2023/unlocking-the-power-of-machine-learning-with-mlc-llm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Machine Learning Compilation for LLM, or &lt;a href=&#34;https://mlc.ai/mlc-llm/docs/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;MLC LLM&lt;/a&gt;, is a cutting-edge universal deployment solution for large language models. In this blog post, we&amp;rsquo;ll guide you through the setup process and show you how to harness the immense potential of MLC LLM.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;setting-up-your-environment&#34;&gt;Setting Up Your Environment&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To get started with MLC LLM, you need to set up your environment properly. Follow these steps:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-install-tvm&#34;&gt;1. Install TVM&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://tvm.apache.org/docs/install/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;TVM&lt;/a&gt;  is a critical component for MLC LLM. You can install it locally using pip:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Utilizing vLLM for Efficient Language Model Serving</title>
      <link>https://seehiong.github.io/archives/2023/utilizing-vllm-for-efficient-language-model-serving/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 20:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://seehiong.github.io/archives/2023/utilizing-vllm-for-efficient-language-model-serving/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://vllm.ai/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;vLLM&lt;/a&gt; is an open-source library designed for rapid LLM (Large Language Model) inference and deployment. It leverages their novel algorithm called &lt;strong&gt;PagedAttention&lt;/strong&gt;, which optimizes the management of attention keys and values.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;preparation&#34;&gt;Preparation&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this blog post, I will share my experience of utilizing vLLM on a WSL (Windows Subsystem for Linux) instance running Ubuntu 22.04. Let&amp;rsquo;s start by setting up the environment:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;installing-wsl-and-configuring-ubuntu&#34;&gt;Installing WSL and Configuring Ubuntu&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Begin by installing WSL and configuring it to use Ubuntu as the default distribution:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
