<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Whisper on See Hiong&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://seehiong.github.io/tags/whisper/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Whisper on See Hiong&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2024 20:00:00 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://seehiong.github.io/tags/whisper/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Audio Generation with NVIDIA Jetson Orin NX</title>
      <link>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2024/08/audio-generation-with-nvidia-jetson-orin-nx/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2024 20:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2024/08/audio-generation-with-nvidia-jetson-orin-nx/</guid>
      <description>This post explores the audio generation capabilities of the NVIDIA Jetson Orin NX. It covers transcribing audio using Whisper, setting up text-to-speech (TTS) and automatic speech recognition (ASR) with Llamaspeak, and preparing the RIVA server for advanced speech AI applications. Detailed instructions and command examples are provided, making it easy for developers to experiment with these tools on the Jetson platform.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to summarize YouTube Videos in Minutes (II)</title>
      <link>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2023/06/how-to-summarize-youtube-videos-in-minutes-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2023 20:00:00 +2000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2023/06/how-to-summarize-youtube-videos-in-minutes-ii/</guid>
      <description>In this comprehensive guide, I explore AI-powered techniques to extract and summarize YouTube videos using tools like Whisper.cpp, GPT4All, LLaMA.cpp, and OpenAI models. I detail the step-by-step process, from setting up the environment to transcribing audio and leveraging AI for summarization. Despite encountering issues with GPT4All&amp;rsquo;s accuracy, alternative approaches using LLaMA.cpp and OpenAI models provide versatile summarization options. The tutorial aims to empower researchers, content creators, and information enthusiasts to efficiently analyze and summarize YouTube content using cutting-edge AI technologies.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
