<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Storage on See Hiong&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://seehiong.github.io/tags/storage/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Storage on See Hiong&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Jun 2021 20:00:00 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://seehiong.github.io/tags/storage/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Pi Cluster with Longhorn</title>
      <link>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2021/06/pi-cluster-with-longhorn/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jun 2021 20:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2021/06/pi-cluster-with-longhorn/</guid>
      <description>I documented my journey setting up a Raspberry Pi Cluster with Longhorn for simplified cloud-native persistent block storage. The process took 30 minutes and assumed a functional Raspberry Pi Cluster. I prepared the environment by installing Helm, Calico CLI, and optionally, Kubernetes Dashboard. Then, I detailed the installation of Longhorn with Helm, including verification steps. Accessing Longhorn involved port-forwarding to the frontend service. The result: a highly available persistent storage solution for my Raspberry Pi Cluster, as depicted in the Longhorn dashboard. I addressed troubleshooting issues related to Calico and Longhorn uninstallation, ensuring a smooth experience.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>External Storage</title>
      <link>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2020/06/external-storage/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 20:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2020/06/external-storage/</guid>
      <description>Expanding my Raspberry Pi Cluster&amp;rsquo;s storage with an external 640GB USB hard disk took 35 minutes. After mounting the external storage and addressing troubleshooting issues, I configured MicroK8s default storage to utilize the added space. Despite encountering errors, a reset and careful configuration solved the problem. Adding leaf nodes for MicroK8s and troubleshooting service unavailability for the dashboard completed the setup. I also disabled and re-enabled addons, ensuring a smooth integration of external storage with my MicroK8s cluster. Accessing the Kubernetes dashboard and checking nodes confirmed a successful expansion.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NAS Server</title>
      <link>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2020/06/nas-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2020 20:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2020/06/nas-server/</guid>
      <description>Repurposing my Raspberry Pi 3B into a NAS server using OpenMediaVault (OMV) was a 90-minute project. I opted for Raspberry Pi OS Lite, ensuring its integrity with MD5 &amp;amp; SHA checksums. Win32DiskImager facilitated OS installation on a 16GB SD card. After powering up, I updated the OS, configured settings, and initiated OMV installation using commands provided by developers. Post-installation, I accessed OMV through the Pi&amp;rsquo;s IP address, configured settings, added a user, mounted an external HDD, created a shared folder, and enabled SMB/CIFS service. Following these steps, I successfully owned a personal OMV on Raspberry Pi!</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
