<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Phi2 on See Hiong&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://seehiong.github.io/tags/phi2/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Phi2 on See Hiong&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 20:00:00 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://seehiong.github.io/tags/phi2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Integrating NFS for Improved Scalability</title>
      <link>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2024/01/integrating-nfs-for-improved-scalability/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 20:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2024/01/integrating-nfs-for-improved-scalability/</guid>
      <description>In this post, we explored the integration of NFS to enhance scalability in deploying LLM models within a home lab. Setting up NFS involved connecting to a TerraMaster NAS, and the K3s cluster was configured to dynamically provision storage. With NFS in place, the deployment process became more efficient, eliminating the need to rebuild images for each new model introduction. The post detailed the setup steps, from configuring NFS and K3s to deploying LLM models dynamically. This approach simplifies the scaling of Language Models, providing a centralized and scalable storage solution through NFS in a Kubernetes environment.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Streamlining API Management with Kong</title>
      <link>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2023/12/streamlining-api-management-with-kong/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 20:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2023/12/streamlining-api-management-with-kong/</guid>
      <description>This comprehensive guide walks you through integrating Kong, a powerful unified API platform, into your home lab environment. Starting with Docker installation and a custom Kong image, it covers PostgreSQL deployment, MetalLB setup for load balancing, and Kong service and route configuration. The post concludes with troubleshooting tips and instructions for deploying your customized Kong image in a K3s cluster. This step-by-step tutorial empowers you to efficiently manage APIs in your home lab using Kong.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deploying OpenAI-Compatible LLAMA CPP Server with K3S</title>
      <link>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2023/12/deploying-openai-compatible-llama-cpp-server-with-k3s/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 20:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2023/12/deploying-openai-compatible-llama-cpp-server-with-k3s/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I expand my Home Lab by adding a perpetual LLAMA model for on-demand inferencing. The steps involve crafting a Dockerfile, packaging Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s Phi2 model, and deploying it with K3S. This ensures a continuously accessible LLAMA server for seamless integration into various inferencing projects.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Running LLaMA server in local machine</title>
      <link>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2023/05/running-llama-server-in-local-machine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 May 2023 20:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2023/05/running-llama-server-in-local-machine/</guid>
      <description>In continuation from my previous post, I prepared the environment using Pipenv and installed the OpenAI-like web server with specific CMAKE arguments. Running the server with a provided model was straightforward. To create an SSH tunnel to the remote Ubuntu machine from my Windows PC, I used PuTTY, configuring it to forward port 8888. Connecting from BYO-GPT involved adjusting the server endpoint in the Dart file. This seamless integration allowed me to access the Open API for the LLAMA CPP server and successfully connect BYO-GPT to the specified server.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Running LLaMA model locally</title>
      <link>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2023/04/running-llama-model-locally/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Apr 2023 20:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2023/04/running-llama-model-locally/</guid>
      <description>In this thorough guide, I prepared my Ubuntu machine (32GB) for the LLaMA (Language Model) build. Following Georgi Gergano&amp;rsquo;s llama.cpp, I executed CMake commands, ensuring the correct tag and building the model successfully. I downloaded Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s Phi2 model in GGUF format, enabling local execution without exposing prompts or data. Running the Phi2 model showcased its capabilities in a few-shot interaction, providing accurate responses. Additionally, I explored optional OpenBLAS integration for improved speed, offering insights into the installation and rebuild process.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
