<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>OpenBLAS on See Hiong&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://seehiong.github.io/tags/openblas/</link>
    <description>Recent content in OpenBLAS on See Hiong&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://seehiong.github.io/tags/openblas/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Unleashing the Power of LLaMA Server in Docker Container</title>
      <link>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2023/07/unleashing-the-power-of-llama-server-in-docker-container/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jul 2023 20:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2023/07/unleashing-the-power-of-llama-server-in-docker-container/</guid>
      <description>After completing the Generative AI with Large Language Models course, I&amp;rsquo;m thrilled to share my Dockerized experience running the LLaMA model. The guide covers setting up the project structure, creating a FastAPI application, and Dockerizing it. Additionally, I showcase building an AI chatbot, integrating it with FastAPI, HuggingFace embeddings, and LLaMA. The Docker environment loads the LLM and allows seamless interactions with PDFs. I conclude by enhancing performance with OpenBLAS, significantly reducing inferencing time. Explore the power of LLaMA Server in a Docker container for transformative AI experiences! 🚀</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building ChatBot for your PDF files with LangChain</title>
      <link>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2023/05/building-chatbot-for-your-pdf-files-with-langchain/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2023 20:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2023/05/building-chatbot-for-your-pdf-files-with-langchain/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I extend the use case from my previous post to demonstrate building a ChatBot for PDF files using LangChain. In the preparation phase, I install Chroma, an open-source embedding database, and ingest a PDF file using PyPDFLoader. I then split the document into chunks and use Chroma&amp;rsquo;s default embeddings. Due to a potential issue, I provide an alternative embedding approach. Next, I load a local LLaMA model, prepare for question-answering, and run queries using RetrievalQAWithSourcesChain. I also touch on running with OpenBLAS for optimization. The guide empowers users to explore personalized question-answering over their PDF documents.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Running LLaMA model locally</title>
      <link>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2023/04/running-llama-model-locally/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Apr 2023 20:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2023/04/running-llama-model-locally/</guid>
      <description>In this thorough guide, I prepared my Ubuntu machine (32GB) for the LLaMA (Language Model) build. Following Georgi Gergano&amp;rsquo;s llama.cpp, I executed CMake commands, ensuring the correct tag and building the model successfully. I downloaded Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s Phi2 model in GGUF format, enabling local execution without exposing prompts or data. Running the Phi2 model showcased its capabilities in a few-shot interaction, providing accurate responses. Additionally, I explored optional OpenBLAS integration for improved speed, offering insights into the installation and rebuild process.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
