<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Talos on See Hiong&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://seehiong.github.io/tags/talos/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Talos on See Hiong&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2024 20:00:00 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://seehiong.github.io/tags/talos/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Deploy Microservices with Talos Locally</title>
      <link>https://seehiong.github.io/2024/deploy-microservices-with-talos-locally/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2024 20:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://seehiong.github.io/2024/deploy-microservices-with-talos-locally/</guid>
      <description>In this guide, we walk through deploying the Google Cloud Microservices Demo locally using Talos Linux in a VirtualBox VM. This step-by-step tutorial replicates a GKE environment, enabling seamless integration of microservices in a local Kubernetes cluster. We cover Talos installation, setting up the microservices demo, integrating MetalLB for load balancing, and optional Istio service mesh and Kiali observability for advanced monitoring. This approach is perfect for developers looking to simulate cloud environments locally and ensure their microservices run smoothly before deploying to production.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Talos Linux: Setting Up a Secure, Immutable Kubernetes Cluster</title>
      <link>https://seehiong.github.io/2024/talos-linux-setting-up-a-secure-immutable-kubernetes-cluster/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 08:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://seehiong.github.io/2024/talos-linux-setting-up-a-secure-immutable-kubernetes-cluster/</guid>
      <description>This post guides you through setting up a secure, immutable Kubernetes cluster using Talos Linux. It covers installing Talos on control and worker nodes, configuring local storage with hostPath and Local Path Provisioner, and setting up the Kubernetes Dashboard with an admin user for cluster management. With Talos Linux, you achieve a minimal, API-managed Kubernetes environment without SSH or systemd, making it ideal for a secure and reliable homelab or production setup.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
