<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>MinIO on See Hiong&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://seehiong.github.io/tags/minio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in MinIO on See Hiong&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 20:00:00 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://seehiong.github.io/tags/minio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>From Model to HDB App</title>
      <link>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2025/04/from-model-to-hdb-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 20:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2025/04/from-model-to-hdb-app/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I demonstrated how to deploy a Jupyter notebook using the jupyter-tensorflow-full image in Kubeflow, develop an HDB resale price predictor app with Streamlit, and access it via port forwarding. The setup runs locally and showcases how to bring together machine learning, visualization, and interactivity in a seamless development workflow within Kubeflow.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Feature Impact on HDB predictions</title>
      <link>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2025/04/feature-impact-on-hdb-predictions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2025 10:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2025/04/feature-impact-on-hdb-predictions/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I explore the impact of different feature sets on XGBoost model performance for HDB resale price prediction. By combining numerical, categorical, and engineered features, I conducted a series of experiments and tracked their performance using MLflow. The results reveal how thoughtful feature engineering and selection can significantly influence metrics like RMSE, MAE, and R²—offering valuable insights into building more accurate predictive models.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building Your First Kubeflow Pipeline: A Step-by-Step Guide</title>
      <link>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2024/07/building-your-first-kubeflow-pipeline-a-step-by-step-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2024 10:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2024/07/building-your-first-kubeflow-pipeline-a-step-by-step-guide/</guid>
      <description>In this blog post, I guide you through creating and running your first Kubeflow pipeline. We&amp;rsquo;ll start with the &amp;ldquo;Hello World&amp;rdquo; example, demonstrate how to manage sequential and shared pipelines, and explore artifact storage with MinIO. Additionally, I&amp;rsquo;ll introduce K9s, a powerful terminal-based UI for managing your Kubernetes clusters efficiently. By the end, you&amp;rsquo;ll have a solid understanding of setting up and managing Kubeflow pipelines in your machine learning workflows.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
