<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kubeflow on See Hiong&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://seehiong.github.io/tags/kubeflow/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Kubeflow on See Hiong&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2024 08:00:00 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://seehiong.github.io/tags/kubeflow/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Integrating MLflow and Kubeflow on Talos</title>
      <link>https://seehiong.github.io/2024/integrating-mlflow-and-kubeflow-on-talos/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2024 08:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://seehiong.github.io/2024/integrating-mlflow-and-kubeflow-on-talos/</guid>
      <description>This post details the installation of MLflow and Kubeflow on a Talos HomeLab cluster. It covers the setup process, including Talos configuration, local-path and NFS provisioning, and Metallb installation. Step-by-step instructions are provided for deploying Kubeflow, followed by the installation of MLflow for managing the machine learning lifecycle. Finally, the post illustrates how to log experiments and models in MLflow and perform inference, demonstrating a seamless integration of these tools for enhanced machine learning operations.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building Your First Kubeflow Pipeline: A Step-by-Step Guide</title>
      <link>https://seehiong.github.io/2024/building-your-first-kubeflow-pipeline-a-step-by-step-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2024 10:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://seehiong.github.io/2024/building-your-first-kubeflow-pipeline-a-step-by-step-guide/</guid>
      <description>In this blog post, I guide you through creating and running your first Kubeflow pipeline. We&amp;rsquo;ll start with the &amp;ldquo;Hello World&amp;rdquo; example, demonstrate how to manage sequential and shared pipelines, and explore artifact storage with MinIO. Additionally, I&amp;rsquo;ll introduce K9s, a powerful terminal-based UI for managing your Kubernetes clusters efficiently. By the end, you&amp;rsquo;ll have a solid understanding of setting up and managing Kubeflow pipelines in your machine learning workflows.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Setting Up and Using KServe with Kubeflow</title>
      <link>https://seehiong.github.io/2024/setting-up-and-using-kserve-with-kubeflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2024 10:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://seehiong.github.io/2024/setting-up-and-using-kserve-with-kubeflow/</guid>
      <description>In this post, we explore KServe, a model inference platform on Kubernetes designed for scalability. Building on our previous Kubeflow guide, we detail how to set up your first KServe endpoint, make predictions, and troubleshoot common issues. Follow our step-by-step instructions to seamlessly integrate KServe with your Kubeflow environment and enhance your machine learning deployment process.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Setting Up Kubeflow on Kubernetes: A Step-by-Step Guide</title>
      <link>https://seehiong.github.io/2024/setting-up-kubeflow-on-kubernetes-a-step-by-step-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2024 10:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://seehiong.github.io/2024/setting-up-kubeflow-on-kubernetes-a-step-by-step-guide/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I provide a comprehensive guide to setting up Kubeflow, a machine learning toolkit for Kubernetes. From initial preparation and downloading necessary binaries to installing all Kubeflow components and troubleshooting common issues, this step-by-step tutorial ensures a smooth installation process. You&amp;rsquo;ll also learn how to create your first notebook and resolve potential errors, making it easier to leverage Kubeflow&amp;rsquo;s powerful features for your machine learning projects.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
