<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Helm on See Hiong&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://seehiong.github.io/tags/helm/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Helm on See Hiong&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 May 2025 20:00:00 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://seehiong.github.io/tags/helm/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Deploying KServe on OKE</title>
      <link>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2025/05/deploying-kserve-on-oke/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2025 20:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2025/05/deploying-kserve-on-oke/</guid>
      <description>This post demonstrated how to deploy an XGBoost model using KServe on Oracle Kubernetes Engine (OKE). Starting from model upload to Object Storage, we served the model via KServe and exposed it through Istio Gateway. Instead of deploying the frontend in-cluster, we built a Streamlit app hosted on Streamlit Community Cloud, which sends requests to the public inference endpoint. This end-to-end setup showcases a scalable and cloud-native ML deployment pipeline on OCI, separating model serving and user interface layers for flexibility and ease of maintenance.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Setting Up Kafka with MicroK8s and Multipass</title>
      <link>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2024/08/setting-up-kafka-with-microk8s-and-multipass/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2024 10:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2024/08/setting-up-kafka-with-microk8s-and-multipass/</guid>
      <description>My homelab is a playground for experimenting with various tools and setups. However, for Proof of Concept (POC) environments, a lightweight and portable setup is often more suitable. In this post, I will guide you through setting up a MicroK8s environment in a virtual machine using Multipass. This POC demonstrates how Kafka can be set up in this environment.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deploying Budibase in HomeLab</title>
      <link>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2024/02/deploying-budibase-in-homelab/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2024 10:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2024/02/deploying-budibase-in-homelab/</guid>
      <description>This post outlines the process of installing Budibase in a HomeLab environment, starting with testing it on Docker Desktop and then deploying it using Helm in Kubernetes. It guides through setting up an admin user, building the first app by creating a database, designing an application form, and configuring submission actions. The summary encapsulates the steps involved in testing, deploying, and building an application with Budibase, highlighting key actions such as Docker Compose setup, Helm installation, app creation, and deployment in a concise manner.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Kong Ingress Controller (KIC)</title>
      <link>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2024/01/exploring-kong-ingress-controller-kic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 10:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2024/01/exploring-kong-ingress-controller-kic/</guid>
      <description>Embark on a journey into the new year by exploring Kong Ingress Controller (KIC) in your home lab. This guide, transitioning from a previous discussion on Kong Gateway, details the seamless setup of KIC using Helm and K3s. From initial preparations to installing Kong Ingress Controller and Gateway, witness the efficient management of APIs in your home lab environment. Learn to add Kong Ingresses, ensuring optimal routing for various paths. Through concise steps and illustrative visuals, this post simplifies the process, allowing you to experience KIC&amp;rsquo;s capabilities firsthand. Dive into the year with a hands-on exploration of API management with Kong in your home lab. Happy New Year!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pi Cluster with Longhorn</title>
      <link>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2021/06/pi-cluster-with-longhorn/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jun 2021 20:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2021/06/pi-cluster-with-longhorn/</guid>
      <description>I documented my journey setting up a Raspberry Pi Cluster with Longhorn for simplified cloud-native persistent block storage. The process took 30 minutes and assumed a functional Raspberry Pi Cluster. I prepared the environment by installing Helm, Calico CLI, and optionally, Kubernetes Dashboard. Then, I detailed the installation of Longhorn with Helm, including verification steps. Accessing Longhorn involved port-forwarding to the frontend service. The result: a highly available persistent storage solution for my Raspberry Pi Cluster, as depicted in the Longhorn dashboard. I addressed troubleshooting issues related to Calico and Longhorn uninstallation, ensuring a smooth experience.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Helm for K8s Cluster</title>
      <link>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2020/07/helm-for-k8s-cluster/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2020 20:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2020/07/helm-for-k8s-cluster/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve successfully set up Helm as the package manager for my Raspberry Pi Kubernetes Cluster, enabling easy discovery, sharing, and use of Kubernetes software. After installing Helm, I set up the NGINX Ingress Controller using Helm for external access. Additionally, I configured MetalLB as a layer 2 load balancer to manage external IP addresses. Revisiting my Gitea setup, I updated the service configuration to leverage MetalLB, enhancing the overall scalability and efficiency of my Kubernetes environment on Raspberry Pi. Helm proves to be a valuable tool for managing Kubernetes packages effortlessly.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
