<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gitea on See Hiong&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://seehiong.github.io/tags/gitea/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Gitea on See Hiong&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 20:00:00 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://seehiong.github.io/tags/gitea/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>CI/CD Pipeline on Pi Cluster (I)</title>
      <link>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2021/06/ci/cd-pipeline-on-pi-cluster-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 20:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2021/06/ci/cd-pipeline-on-pi-cluster-i/</guid>
      <description>In this series, I documented my journey building a CI/CD pipeline on a Raspberry Pi Cluster, featuring 3 master and 1 worker nodes, all housed in a custom LEGO structure. The setup includes tools like Metallb for load balancing, along with specific volumes for MySQL, Gitea, Jenkins, and Maven-agent. I detailed the installation processes for MySQL, Gitea, Jenkins, and Maven-agent, complete with YAML deployment files. The configuration steps for Jenkins, both for Kubernetes and Gitea integration, were outlined. The troubleshooting section covers issues related to Kubernetes connection errors and finding the Jenkins initial admin password. The final result showcases a functional CI/CD pipeline: when code is committed, it triggers the CI pipeline, with the Maven-agent building and compiling the code successfully.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jenkins Pipeline for K8s Cluster</title>
      <link>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2020/07/jenkins-pipeline-for-k8s-cluster/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2020 20:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2020/07/jenkins-pipeline-for-k8s-cluster/</guid>
      <description>I effortlessly set up a Jenkins Pipeline for my Kubernetes Cluster, enabling seamless continuous integration for my projects. Following my previous post on integrating Jenkins and Gitea, I configured Git and Gitea, creating a declarative Jenkins pipeline. With Gitea webhooks triggering builds on Git commits, I successfully tested the pipeline for a Spring Boot Hello-World application. The pipeline integrates with Git, Maven, and Gitea, ensuring efficient builds and synchronization with each commit. Troubleshooting tips address potential issues, providing a smooth Jenkins experience. Next, I plan to enhance Maven build times in my upcoming guide.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Integrating Jenkins and Gitea</title>
      <link>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2020/07/integrating-jenkins-and-gitea/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2020 20:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2020/07/integrating-jenkins-and-gitea/</guid>
      <description>I seamlessly integrated Jenkins and Gitea, establishing full control over my self-hosted continuous integration (CI) environment. I installed the Gitea plugin on Jenkins, configured Gitea, and set up Jenkins to recognize the Gitea organization. The integration allows automatic build triggers upon committing to the Gitea repository. Additionally, I tested the webhook connection for smooth functionality. With this setup, I&amp;rsquo;m ready to dive into the CI workflow for my Spring Boot application in the upcoming post. Stay tuned for more!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gitea for K8s Cluster</title>
      <link>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2020/07/gitea-for-k8s-cluster/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2020 20:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2020/07/gitea-for-k8s-cluster/</guid>
      <description>In my recent endeavor, I spent 40 minutes setting up Gitea on my Kubernetes Pi cluster, granting me absolute control over personal Git repositories. I seamlessly integrated MySQL, using Docker images and Kubernetes configurations. The meticulous setup involved creating necessary paths on an external HDD, configuring persistent volumes, and ensuring a smooth deployment. I prepared MySQL for Gitea, creating a user, database, and granting privileges. Gitea installation via Docker and subsequent exposure to external access using NodePort were executed flawlessly. A troubleshooting tip addressed a MySQL access issue. Now, my Gitea on Kubernetes Pi Cluster is fully operational for efficient repository management.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gitea for MicroK8s Cluster</title>
      <link>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2020/06/gitea-for-microk8s-cluster/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2020 20:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2020/06/gitea-for-microk8s-cluster/</guid>
      <description>I dedicated 45 minutes to set up Gitea on my Raspberry Pi cluster using MicroK8s. Gitea, a self-hosted Git service, grants my team cost savings and enhanced server control. I ensured a smooth installation by preparing MySQL, creating required paths on an external HDD, and configuring persistent volumes. Following MySQL setup, I seamlessly prepared the database and moved on to setting up Gitea with Docker, utilizing a docker-compose.yml file. After injecting images into MicroK8s cache, I exposed Gitea externally using NodePort. Troubleshooting tips were handy, addressing MySQL connection issues. My self-hosted Git service is now ready for efficient collaboration.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
