<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>NFS on See Hiong&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://seehiong.github.io/tags/nfs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in NFS on See Hiong&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 08:00:00 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://seehiong.github.io/tags/nfs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Talos Linux: Setting Up a Secure, Immutable Kubernetes Cluster</title>
      <link>https://seehiong.github.io/2024/talos-linux-setting-up-a-secure-immutable-kubernetes-cluster/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 08:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://seehiong.github.io/2024/talos-linux-setting-up-a-secure-immutable-kubernetes-cluster/</guid>
      <description>This post guides you through setting up a secure, immutable Kubernetes cluster using Talos Linux. It covers installing Talos on control and worker nodes, configuring local storage with hostPath and Local Path Provisioner, and setting up the Kubernetes Dashboard with an admin user for cluster management. With Talos Linux, you achieve a minimal, API-managed Kubernetes environment without SSH or systemd, making it ideal for a secure and reliable homelab or production setup.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deploying Budibase in HomeLab</title>
      <link>https://seehiong.github.io/2024/deploying-budibase-in-homelab/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2024 10:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://seehiong.github.io/2024/deploying-budibase-in-homelab/</guid>
      <description>This post outlines the process of installing Budibase in a HomeLab environment, starting with testing it on Docker Desktop and then deploying it using Helm in Kubernetes. It guides through setting up an admin user, building the first app by creating a database, designing an application form, and configuring submission actions. The summary encapsulates the steps involved in testing, deploying, and building an application with Budibase, highlighting key actions such as Docker Compose setup, Helm installation, app creation, and deployment in a concise manner.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Integrating NFS for Improved Scalability</title>
      <link>https://seehiong.github.io/2024/integrating-nfs-for-improved-scalability/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 20:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://seehiong.github.io/2024/integrating-nfs-for-improved-scalability/</guid>
      <description>In this post, we explored the integration of NFS to enhance scalability in deploying LLM models within a home lab. Setting up NFS involved connecting to a TerraMaster NAS, and the K3s cluster was configured to dynamically provision storage. With NFS in place, the deployment process became more efficient, eliminating the need to rebuild images for each new model introduction. The post detailed the setup steps, from configuring NFS and K3s to deploying LLM models dynamically. This approach simplifies the scaling of Language Models, providing a centralized and scalable storage solution through NFS in a Kubernetes environment.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
