<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>XGBoost on See Hiong&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://seehiong.github.io/tags/xgboost/</link>
    <description>Recent content in XGBoost on See Hiong&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 10:00:00 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://seehiong.github.io/tags/xgboost/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Building HDB Agent</title>
      <link>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2025/10/building-hdb-agent/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 10:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2025/10/building-hdb-agent/</guid>
      <description>Discover how I built HDB Agent, an AI-driven system leveraging AWS Bedrock AgentCore, Lambda, and Athena to analyze Singapore’s HDB resale market. The architecture combines serverless, event-driven design with hybrid infrastructure—integrating S3, RDS Aurora, and CloudFormation for modular deployment. Intelligent query routing directs requests to the most efficient backend—XGBoost for price prediction, Athena for analytics, PostgreSQL MCP for comparisons, and Bedrock LLMs for contextual insights—creating a powerful, scalable, and cost-efficient agentic AI solution.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Model to HDB App</title>
      <link>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2025/04/from-model-to-hdb-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 20:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2025/04/from-model-to-hdb-app/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I demonstrated how to deploy a Jupyter notebook using the jupyter-tensorflow-full image in Kubeflow, develop an HDB resale price predictor app with Streamlit, and access it via port forwarding. The setup runs locally and showcases how to bring together machine learning, visualization, and interactivity in a seamless development workflow within Kubeflow.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Feature Impact on HDB predictions</title>
      <link>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2025/04/feature-impact-on-hdb-predictions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2025 10:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2025/04/feature-impact-on-hdb-predictions/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I explore the impact of different feature sets on XGBoost model performance for HDB resale price prediction. By combining numerical, categorical, and engineered features, I conducted a series of experiments and tracked their performance using MLflow. The results reveal how thoughtful feature engineering and selection can significantly influence metrics like RMSE, MAE, and R²—offering valuable insights into building more accurate predictive models.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
