<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>WizardLM on See Hiong&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://seehiong.github.io/tags/wizardlm/</link>
    <description>Recent content in WizardLM on See Hiong&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 20:00:00 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://seehiong.github.io/tags/wizardlm/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Boosting Inference Speed: SSD and GPU Acceleration</title>
      <link>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2023/11/boosting-inference-speed-ssd-and-gpu-acceleration/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 20:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2023/11/boosting-inference-speed-ssd-and-gpu-acceleration/</guid>
      <description>Embarking on an exhilarating upgrade journey, I chronicle the seamless migration to the powerful Lexar NM790 SSD and unveil the secrets behind turbocharging Langchain4j&amp;rsquo;s inferencing speed. With Clonezilla&amp;rsquo;s reliability, my Windows 11 transition to this SSD was flawless, offering a tangible boost. The GPU acceleration saga unfolded with CUDA installation and the NVIDIA Container Toolkit magic, resulting in a high-speed universe. Launching the LocalAI image in a GPU Docker container revealed the grand finale—a remarkable surge in Langchain4j&amp;rsquo;s inference speed. This transformation invites tech enthusiasts to explore elevated performance and redefine possibilities.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RAG over Java code with Langchain4j</title>
      <link>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2023/11/rag-over-java-code-with-langchain4j/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Nov 2023 20:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2023/11/rag-over-java-code-with-langchain4j/</guid>
      <description>In my latest post, I delve into seamlessly integrating Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG) with Java code using Langchain4j. Drawing inspiration from RAG over code, I explore Java Parser&amp;rsquo;s potential for robust codebase analysis. The pivotal JavaParsingService and EmbeddingStoreService orchestrate this integration, enabling users to effortlessly load Java projects and glean profound insights. The enhanced controller boasts user-friendly endpoints, fostering dynamic interactions. Witness Retrieval-Augmented Generation breathe life into Java code, from codebase ingestion to insightful querying with models like gpt4all-j, WizardLM, and OpenAI. This narrative unveils the nuanced capabilities of RAG in querying Java codebases.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
