<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kong on See Hiong&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://seehiong.github.io/tags/kong/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Kong on See Hiong&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2024 10:00:00 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://seehiong.github.io/tags/kong/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Integration of Kong into AI Workflow</title>
      <link>https://seehiong.github.io/archives/2024/integration-of-kong-into-ai-workflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2024 10:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://seehiong.github.io/archives/2024/integration-of-kong-into-ai-workflow/</guid>
      <description>This comprehensive guide navigates through configuring Kong OSS and Kong Ingress Controller (KIC), seamlessly integrating Kong into an AI workflow. Starting with Kong OSS configuration, the tutorial covers updating environment variables and service ports. The Langchain4j application is then adapted to leverage Kong API, allowing for flexible path-based APIs. Additionally, potential timeout issues are addressed. The guide concludes with a demonstration of Kong Ingress Controller configuration, emphasizing optimal settings for specific use cases. Whether through Kong OSS or KIC, readers gain insights into enhancing API management and integration within their AI workflows.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Kong Ingress Controller (KIC)</title>
      <link>https://seehiong.github.io/archives/2024/exploring-kong-ingress-controller-kic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 10:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://seehiong.github.io/archives/2024/exploring-kong-ingress-controller-kic/</guid>
      <description>Embark on a journey into the new year by exploring Kong Ingress Controller (KIC) in your home lab. This guide, transitioning from a previous discussion on Kong Gateway, details the seamless setup of KIC using Helm and K3s. From initial preparations to installing Kong Ingress Controller and Gateway, witness the efficient management of APIs in your home lab environment. Learn to add Kong Ingresses, ensuring optimal routing for various paths. Through concise steps and illustrative visuals, this post simplifies the process, allowing you to experience KIC&amp;rsquo;s capabilities firsthand. Dive into the year with a hands-on exploration of API management with Kong in your home lab. Happy New Year!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Streamlining API Management with Kong</title>
      <link>https://seehiong.github.io/archives/2023/streamlining-api-management-with-kong/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 20:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://seehiong.github.io/archives/2023/streamlining-api-management-with-kong/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this comprehensive guide, we will walk through the process of integrating &lt;a href=&#34;https://konghq.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Kong&lt;/a&gt;, a robust unified API platform, into our home lab environment.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;prerequistes&#34;&gt;Prerequistes&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To begin, I will start with a fresh Ubuntu server instance. We&amp;rsquo;ll start by installing Docker and configuring it for non-root usage:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34; data-lang=&#34;shell&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;sudo apt install docker.io&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;sudo usermod -aG docker pi&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;# Run Docker without sudo by logging back in or executing this&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;su - pi&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pr</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
