<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts from 2026 on See Hiong&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2026/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts from 2026 on See Hiong&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 10:00:00 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2026/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Blender MCP for n8n</title>
      <link>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2026/02/blender-mcp-for-n8n/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 10:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2026/02/blender-mcp-for-n8n/</guid>
      <description>Blender MCP for n8n is a Model Context Protocol (MCP) bridge that allows n8n AI workflows to directly control Blender’s Python API. The system combines a Blender addon, a stateless/stateful MCP bridge server, and a record-and-replay session framework to enable deterministic, reproducible 3D scene generation from natural language. With 70+ structured tools spanning modeling, materials, animation, architectural workflows, and MEP systems, complex scenes can be constructed, tested, and replayed reliably through AI-directed tool calls.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering a Narrative Multiverse</title>
      <link>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2026/02/engineering-a-narrative-multiverse/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 10:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2026/02/engineering-a-narrative-multiverse/</guid>
      <description>Living Storybook explores what happens when storytelling is treated as a system rather than a stream of text. This post walks through the architecture behind a multiverse-aware writing tool that supports branching narratives, causal persistence, and human–AI co-authoring. From timeline reconstruction and chapter blueprints to validation guards and stateful characters, it shows how narrative, planning, and control flow come together to make stories that can truly diverge — without losing coherence.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
