<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Spring Boot on See Hiong&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://seehiong.github.io/tags/spring-boot/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Spring Boot on See Hiong&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://seehiong.github.io/tags/spring-boot/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>RAG over Java code with Langchain4j</title>
      <link>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2023/11/rag-over-java-code-with-langchain4j/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Nov 2023 20:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2023/11/rag-over-java-code-with-langchain4j/</guid>
      <description>In my latest post, I delve into seamlessly integrating Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG) with Java code using Langchain4j. Drawing inspiration from RAG over code, I explore Java Parser&amp;rsquo;s potential for robust codebase analysis. The pivotal JavaParsingService and EmbeddingStoreService orchestrate this integration, enabling users to effortlessly load Java projects and glean profound insights. The enhanced controller boasts user-friendly endpoints, fostering dynamic interactions. Witness Retrieval-Augmented Generation breathe life into Java code, from codebase ingestion to insightful querying with models like gpt4all-j, WizardLM, and OpenAI. This narrative unveils the nuanced capabilities of RAG in querying Java codebases.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building an AI Application with Langchain4j</title>
      <link>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2023/11/building-an-ai-application-with-langchain4j/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2023 20:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2023/11/building-an-ai-application-with-langchain4j/</guid>
      <description>I embarked on a journey to harness the capabilities of Langchain4j, crafting a powerful AI application in Java using the local language model. Utilizing Spring Boot, Postman, and various Langchain4j components, I explored setting up, implementing a chat service, integrating custom tools, embedding functionality with Chroma, translation, persistence, retrieval, and streaming services. The blog post serves as a comprehensive guide for building personalized AI applications, showcasing the versatility and potential of Langchain4j in Java development.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
