<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>TensorFlow on See Hiong&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://seehiong.github.io/tags/tensorflow/</link>
    <description>Recent content in TensorFlow on See Hiong&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2025 10:00:00 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://seehiong.github.io/tags/tensorflow/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Feature Impact on HDB predictions</title>
      <link>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2025/04/feature-impact-on-hdb-predictions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2025 10:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2025/04/feature-impact-on-hdb-predictions/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I explore the impact of different feature sets on XGBoost model performance for HDB resale price prediction. By combining numerical, categorical, and engineered features, I conducted a series of experiments and tracked their performance using MLflow. The results reveal how thoughtful feature engineering and selection can significantly influence metrics like RMSE, MAE, and R²—offering valuable insights into building more accurate predictive models.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MNIST Digit Classifier in TensorFlow</title>
      <link>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2025/04/mnist-digit-classifier-in-tensorflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Apr 2025 20:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2025/04/mnist-digit-classifier-in-tensorflow/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I walk through building a simple feedforward neural network using TensorFlow to classify handwritten digits from the MNIST dataset. From data preprocessing to training, evaluation, and visualizing predictions, this hands-on project reinforces key deep learning concepts covered in Andrew Ng’s course. The model achieved over 97% accuracy on the test set, and I also explored prediction confidence and misclassified samples. A solid foundation for experimenting with more advanced architectures ahead.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
