<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Chroma on See Hiong&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://seehiong.github.io/tags/chroma/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Chroma on See Hiong&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2024 20:00:00 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://seehiong.github.io/tags/chroma/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Building an AI Knowledge Assistant</title>
      <link>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2024/11/building-an-ai-knowledge-assistant/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2024 20:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2024/11/building-an-ai-knowledge-assistant/</guid>
      <description>Learn how to build an AI-powered knowledge assistant using Python. This guide covers data ingestion from sources like PDFs, deploying a FastAPI-based API, and querying the assistant for detailed answers. Using advanced retrieval mechanisms, the assistant provides contextually relevant responses. You&amp;rsquo;ll also explore a working example with the CQRS design pattern. The complete project code is available on &#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/seehiong/ai-knowledge-assistant&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreferrer&#34; &gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&#xA;.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI Integration: LocalAI, Chroma, and Langchain4j</title>
      <link>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2023/12/ai-integration-localai-chroma-and-langchain4j/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2023 20:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2023/12/ai-integration-localai-chroma-and-langchain4j/</guid>
      <description>Explore AI integration in a home lab with LocalAI, Chroma, and Langchain4j. Begin by creating a custom LocalAI image, deploying it alongside Chroma, and configuring the Kubernetes environment. The post details deploying and exposing services, ensuring seamless communication between applications. Learn to modify endpoints in the Langchain4j application for smooth integration with the Home Lab setup. With a focus on simplicity, this guide empowers users to harness the capabilities of these AI tools within a controlled home environment, fostering experimentation and development.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RAG over Java code with Langchain4j</title>
      <link>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2023/11/rag-over-java-code-with-langchain4j/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Nov 2023 20:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2023/11/rag-over-java-code-with-langchain4j/</guid>
      <description>In my latest post, I delve into seamlessly integrating Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG) with Java code using Langchain4j. Drawing inspiration from RAG over code, I explore Java Parser&amp;rsquo;s potential for robust codebase analysis. The pivotal JavaParsingService and EmbeddingStoreService orchestrate this integration, enabling users to effortlessly load Java projects and glean profound insights. The enhanced controller boasts user-friendly endpoints, fostering dynamic interactions. Witness Retrieval-Augmented Generation breathe life into Java code, from codebase ingestion to insightful querying with models like gpt4all-j, WizardLM, and OpenAI. This narrative unveils the nuanced capabilities of RAG in querying Java codebases.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building an AI Application with Langchain4j</title>
      <link>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2023/11/building-an-ai-application-with-langchain4j/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2023 20:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2023/11/building-an-ai-application-with-langchain4j/</guid>
      <description>I embarked on a journey to harness the capabilities of Langchain4j, crafting a powerful AI application in Java using the local language model. Utilizing Spring Boot, Postman, and various Langchain4j components, I explored setting up, implementing a chat service, integrating custom tools, embedding functionality with Chroma, translation, persistence, retrieval, and streaming services. The blog post serves as a comprehensive guide for building personalized AI applications, showcasing the versatility and potential of Langchain4j in Java development.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building ChatBot for your PDF files with LangChain</title>
      <link>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2023/05/building-chatbot-for-your-pdf-files-with-langchain/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2023 20:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2023/05/building-chatbot-for-your-pdf-files-with-langchain/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I extend the use case from my previous post to demonstrate building a ChatBot for PDF files using LangChain. In the preparation phase, I install Chroma, an open-source embedding database, and ingest a PDF file using PyPDFLoader. I then split the document into chunks and use Chroma&amp;rsquo;s default embeddings. Due to a potential issue, I provide an alternative embedding approach. Next, I load a local LLaMA model, prepare for question-answering, and run queries using RetrievalQAWithSourcesChain. I also touch on running with OpenBLAS for optimization. The guide empowers users to explore personalized question-answering over their PDF documents.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
