<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>GPU on See Hiong&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://seehiong.github.io/tags/gpu/</link>
    <description>Recent content in GPU on See Hiong&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://seehiong.github.io/tags/gpu/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Boosting Inference Speed: SSD and GPU Acceleration</title>
      <link>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2023/11/boosting-inference-speed-ssd-and-gpu-acceleration/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 20:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2023/11/boosting-inference-speed-ssd-and-gpu-acceleration/</guid>
      <description>Embarking on an exhilarating upgrade journey, I chronicle the seamless migration to the powerful Lexar NM790 SSD and unveil the secrets behind turbocharging Langchain4j&amp;rsquo;s inferencing speed. With Clonezilla&amp;rsquo;s reliability, my Windows 11 transition to this SSD was flawless, offering a tangible boost. The GPU acceleration saga unfolded with CUDA installation and the NVIDIA Container Toolkit magic, resulting in a high-speed universe. Launching the LocalAI image in a GPU Docker container revealed the grand finale—a remarkable surge in Langchain4j&amp;rsquo;s inference speed. This transformation invites tech enthusiasts to explore elevated performance and redefine possibilities.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Utilizing vLLM for Efficient Language Model Serving</title>
      <link>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2023/08/utilizing-vllm-for-efficient-language-model-serving/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 20:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2023/08/utilizing-vllm-for-efficient-language-model-serving/</guid>
      <description>Embarking on my journey with vLLM, I explore its potential for streamlined Large Language Model (LLM) inference and deployment. The blog details my personal experience setting up vLLM on a Windows Subsystem for Linux (WSL) instance running Ubuntu 22.04. I meticulously guide through installing WSL, NVIDIA GPU drivers, CUDA Toolkit, and Docker for efficient utilization. Delving into vLLM setup within the NVIDIA PyTorch Docker image, I navigate through the installation process and launch the API server. The blog provides insights into querying the model and creating a Docker image snapshot, offering a comprehensive guide to efficient language model serving.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
