<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Orin NX on See Hiong&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://seehiong.github.io/tags/orin-nx/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Orin NX on See Hiong&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2024 20:00:00 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://seehiong.github.io/tags/orin-nx/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Audio Generation with NVIDIA Jetson Orin NX</title>
      <link>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2024/08/audio-generation-with-nvidia-jetson-orin-nx/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2024 20:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2024/08/audio-generation-with-nvidia-jetson-orin-nx/</guid>
      <description>This post explores the audio generation capabilities of the NVIDIA Jetson Orin NX. It covers transcribing audio using Whisper, setting up text-to-speech (TTS) and automatic speech recognition (ASR) with Llamaspeak, and preparing the RIVA server for advanced speech AI applications. Detailed instructions and command examples are provided, making it easy for developers to experiment with these tools on the Jetson platform.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unleashing Text Generation with NVIDIA Jetson Orin NX</title>
      <link>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2024/08/unleashing-text-generation-with-nvidia-jetson-orin-nx/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Aug 2024 20:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2024/08/unleashing-text-generation-with-nvidia-jetson-orin-nx/</guid>
      <description>This post explores the powerful capabilities of NVIDIA Jetson Orin NX for text generation tasks. It covers the setup and use of models like Llama 2 and Llama 3, including installation steps, performance benchmarks, and examples of interactive AI sessions. Additionally, it provides insights into using the Jetson platform for deploying AI models efficiently, with practical tips on getting started and maximizing performance. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re a developer or AI enthusiast, this guide offers a hands-on look at harnessing NVIDIA Jetson&amp;rsquo;s potential for advanced AI applications.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring NVIDIA Jetson Orin NX: Flashing and Setup Guide</title>
      <link>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2024/08/exploring-nvidia-jetson-orin-nx-flashing-and-setup-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 10:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2024/08/exploring-nvidia-jetson-orin-nx-flashing-and-setup-guide/</guid>
      <description>In this guide, I document the process of setting up and flashing the NVIDIA Jetson Orin NX, a powerful embedded AI computer ideal for advanced robotics and generative AI applications. The post covers preparation steps, including selecting the right SSD and downloading the necessary Ubuntu image. I provide a detailed walkthrough of the installation using NVIDIA&amp;rsquo;s SDK Manager, along with troubleshooting tips based on my experience. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re new to the Jetson Orin NX or looking to optimize your setup, this guide offers practical insights and step-by-step instructions to get you started.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
