<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>MCP Toolbox on See Hiong&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://seehiong.github.io/tags/mcp-toolbox/</link>
    <description>Recent content in MCP Toolbox on See Hiong&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 20:00:00 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://seehiong.github.io/tags/mcp-toolbox/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Autonomous DeepAgents for HDB Insights</title>
      <link>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2025/12/autonomous-deepagents-for-hdb-insights/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 20:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2025/12/autonomous-deepagents-for-hdb-insights/</guid>
      <description>This post demonstrates how to build an autonomous DeepAgents-powered pipeline that performs intent extraction, SQL retrieval, and geospatial reasoning to answer real-world HDB property queries. Using LangGraph, MCP Toolbox, PostGIS, and a Dockerized backend, the system provides end-to-end MRT proximity analysis and natural-language search for HDB resale insights.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building a LangGraph Multi-Agent System</title>
      <link>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2025/11/building-a-langgraph-multi-agent-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 18:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2025/11/building-a-langgraph-multi-agent-system/</guid>
      <description>This post walks through building a complete multi-agent system using LangGraph—from a simple deterministic chain to a fully orchestrated ReAct agent and a modular supervisor-led MAS. It integrates Postgres (via MCP Toolbox), Tavily web search, and custom Python tools to analyze Singapore HDB resale data and nearby amenities. Complete with diagrams, code walkthroughs, and LangSmith Studio deployment, this guide demonstrates how to design practical, production-ready agent workflows using LangChain and LangGraph.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ADK Web Multi-Agent System</title>
      <link>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2025/11/adk-web-multi-agent-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2025/11/adk-web-multi-agent-system/</guid>
      <description>This blog post details how I built a multi-agent system using Google&amp;rsquo;s ADK, powered by OpenRouter models, for a web application focused on Singapore&amp;rsquo;s HDB data. The system integrates structured data via PostgreSQL (managed by MCP Toolbox) and general statistics via the Data Commons MCP Tools. The architecture uses a Coordinator/Dispatcher pattern to intelligently route HDB-specific queries to the PostgreSQL agent and general queries to the Data Commons agent, ensuring specialized and efficient data retrieval.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
