<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>TSP on See Hiong&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://seehiong.github.io/tags/tsp/</link>
    <description>Recent content in TSP on See Hiong&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 10:00:00 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://seehiong.github.io/tags/tsp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Building a Flexible Optimizer Framework with Micronaut</title>
      <link>https://seehiong.github.io/2024/designing-an-optimizer-framework/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 10:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://seehiong.github.io/2024/designing-an-optimizer-framework/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Combinatorial optimization problems are fundamental challenges in modern computing, particularly in logistics, network design, and operations research. The &lt;em&gt;Facility Location Problem (FLP)&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Traveling Salesman Problem (TSP)&lt;/em&gt; represent prime examples of these challenges. In this post, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore the development of a sophisticated optimizer framework using Micronaut, featuring real-time progress tracking and a modular, extensible architecture.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With the exciting announcement of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://code.visualstudio.com/blogs/2024/12/18/free-github-copilot&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;free plan for Github Copilot&lt;/a&gt;, we&amp;rsquo;ll leverage AI-assisted development to create our Micronaut Optimizer framework. This powerful combination of tools will help us tackle complex combinatorial optimization problems efficiently.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing TSP with Genetic Algorithms in Micronaut</title>
      <link>https://seehiong.github.io/2024/optimizing-tsp-with-genetic-algorithms-in-micronaut/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2024 20:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://seehiong.github.io/2024/optimizing-tsp-with-genetic-algorithms-in-micronaut/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I explore solving a Traveling Salesman Problem (TSP) involving 200 cities using genetic algorithms within a Micronaut framework. Leveraging techniques like inversion, insertion, and swap mutations, I illustrate how to maintain genetic diversity and improve solution quality over generations. The implementation showcases significant performance improvements compared to previous solvers. This approach combines simulated annealing, genetic algorithms, and local search to tackle complex optimization challenges effectively.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient TSP Solver API with Micronaut</title>
      <link>https://seehiong.github.io/2024/efficient-tsp-solver-api-with-micronaut/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2024 20:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://seehiong.github.io/2024/efficient-tsp-solver-api-with-micronaut/</guid>
      <description>Solve the Travelling Salesman Problem using Choco-solver and convert it into a powerful API with Micronaut. Explore the efficient solution and its integration for optimal city tours.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
