<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>TSP on See Hiong&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://seehiong.github.io/tags/tsp/</link>
    <description>Recent content in TSP on See Hiong&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2025 10:00:00 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://seehiong.github.io/tags/tsp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Building a Vue.js Frontend for Combinatorial Optimization Problems</title>
      <link>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2025/01/building-a-vue.js-frontend-for-combinatorial-optimization-problems/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2025 10:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2025/01/building-a-vue.js-frontend-for-combinatorial-optimization-problems/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I’ll walk you through the development of a Vue.js frontend application designed to complement my previous work on a flexible optimizer framework built with Micronaut. This frontend provides a visual interface for designing, managing, and optimizing workflows, with a focus on solving combinatorial optimization problems like the Traveling Salesman Problem (TSP). The app features a drag-and-drop UI, enabling users to define optimization problems graphically without relying on tools like Postman. By connecting inputs, transformations, and outputs through Workflow Nodes, users can visualize and compare the performance of backend optimization algorithms across different datasets.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building a Flexible Optimizer Framework with Micronaut</title>
      <link>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2024/12/building-a-flexible-optimizer-framework-with-micronaut/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 10:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2024/12/building-a-flexible-optimizer-framework-with-micronaut/</guid>
      <description>This post outlines the design and implementation of the Micronaut Optimizer framework, which solves combinatorial optimization problems like TSP and FLP. It details the architecture, key components, and the use of Flux and PublishSubject for real-time updates. The post also highlights planned enhancements, including additional solver integration, performance optimizations, visualization improvements, and architecture extensions. The complete implementation is available on GitHub, and contributions are welcome.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing TSP with Genetic Algorithms in Micronaut</title>
      <link>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2024/05/optimizing-tsp-with-genetic-algorithms-in-micronaut/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2024 20:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2024/05/optimizing-tsp-with-genetic-algorithms-in-micronaut/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I explore solving a Traveling Salesman Problem (TSP) involving 200 cities using genetic algorithms within a Micronaut framework. Leveraging techniques like inversion, insertion, and swap mutations, I illustrate how to maintain genetic diversity and improve solution quality over generations. The implementation showcases significant performance improvements compared to previous solvers. This approach combines simulated annealing, genetic algorithms, and local search to tackle complex optimization challenges effectively.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient TSP Solver API with Micronaut</title>
      <link>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2024/04/efficient-tsp-solver-api-with-micronaut/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2024 20:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2024/04/efficient-tsp-solver-api-with-micronaut/</guid>
      <description>Solve the Travelling Salesman Problem using Choco-solver and convert it into a powerful API with Micronaut. Explore the efficient solution and its integration for optimal city tours.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
