<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Robotics on See Hiong&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://seehiong.github.io/tags/robotics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Robotics on See Hiong&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2024 20:00:00 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://seehiong.github.io/tags/robotics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Controlling RoArm-M2-S with ROS2</title>
      <link>https://seehiong.github.io/archives/2024/controlling-roarm-m2-s-with-ros2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2024 20:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://seehiong.github.io/archives/2024/controlling-roarm-m2-s-with-ros2/</guid>
      <description>Learn how to set up and control the RoArm-M2-S robotic arm using ROS2 in a virtual environment. This guide walks you through installing VirtualBox, creating a custom Ubuntu VM, setting up ROS2 with MoveIt2, and running driver nodes to control the arm through RViz, MoveIt, keyboard, and a web interface.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wave Rover with Raspberry Pi 4</title>
      <link>https://seehiong.github.io/archives/2024/wave-rover-with-raspberry-pi-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2024 20:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://seehiong.github.io/archives/2024/wave-rover-with-raspberry-pi-4/</guid>
      <description>This post documents using a Raspberry Pi 4 as the main controller for the Wave Rover project. It covers installing Raspberry Pi OS, setting up the UGV_RPI package, enabling VNC, and configuring the Pi camera. Additionally, it details how to control the rover&amp;rsquo;s movement with Python and stream camera feeds via Flask. A sample HTML interface is provided for controlling the rover with arrow keys or buttons. Troubleshooting steps are included for resolving issues related to Picamera2 and V4L2 errors during the setup.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wave Rover: Setup Guide and Troubleshooting Tips</title>
      <link>https://seehiong.github.io/archives/2024/wave-rover-setup-guide-and-troubleshooting-tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2024 10:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://seehiong.github.io/archives/2024/wave-rover-setup-guide-and-troubleshooting-tips/</guid>
      <description>This guide walks you through setting up the Wave Rover, including hardware connections and software configuration. It covers common issues like missing drivers and file errors, providing step-by-step solutions for problems such as the CP2102N USB to UART Bridge Controller and missing libraries like ArduinoJson or Adafruit_GFX. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re troubleshooting hardware connections or resolving compilation errors, this guide ensures a smooth setup process.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
