<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hackathon on See Hiong&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://seehiong.github.io/tags/hackathon/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hackathon on See Hiong&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 10:00:00 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://seehiong.github.io/tags/hackathon/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Engineering a Narrative Multiverse</title>
      <link>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2026/02/engineering-a-narrative-multiverse/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 10:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2026/02/engineering-a-narrative-multiverse/</guid>
      <description>Living Storybook explores what happens when storytelling is treated as a system rather than a stream of text. This post walks through the architecture behind a multiverse-aware writing tool that supports branching narratives, causal persistence, and human–AI co-authoring. From timeline reconstruction and chapter blueprints to validation guards and stateful characters, it shows how narrative, planning, and control flow come together to make stories that can truly diverge — without losing coherence.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Voice-Native Document Intelligence</title>
      <link>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2025/12/voice-native-document-intelligence/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 10:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2025/12/voice-native-document-intelligence/</guid>
      <description>VoiceDoc Agent is a voice-native document intelligence system built for the AI Partner Catalyst hackathon. It transforms static documents into spoken, conversational experiences using Gemini on Vertex AI, ElevenLabs Speech-to-Text and Text-to-Speech, and Datadog observability. The project demonstrates a production-ready, voice-first architecture with expressive narration, persona-aware responses, real-time metrics, and synthetic traffic testing — showcasing how Google Cloud partner services can be composed into a measurable, scalable AI system.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ATS Buddy: Privacy-First Resume AI</title>
      <link>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2025/10/ats-buddy-privacy-first-resume-ai/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 10:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2025/10/ats-buddy-privacy-first-resume-ai/</guid>
      <description>ATS Buddy is an AI-powered resume analysis tool built with AWS Bedrock, Textract, and Comprehend. Designed with a privacy-first approach, it redacts PII before analysis, helping job seekers optimize resumes without exposing personal data. With S3, DynamoDB caching, and serverless workflows, ATS Buddy delivers secure, cost-efficient resume insights—built hackathon-ready.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
