<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>OpenRouter on See Hiong&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://seehiong.github.io/tags/openrouter/</link>
    <description>Recent content in OpenRouter on See Hiong&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 20:00:00 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://seehiong.github.io/tags/openrouter/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Autonomous DeepAgents for HDB Insights</title>
      <link>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2025/12/autonomous-deepagents-for-hdb-insights/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 20:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2025/12/autonomous-deepagents-for-hdb-insights/</guid>
      <description>This post demonstrates how to build an autonomous DeepAgents-powered pipeline that performs intent extraction, SQL retrieval, and geospatial reasoning to answer real-world HDB property queries. Using LangGraph, MCP Toolbox, PostGIS, and a Dockerized backend, the system provides end-to-end MRT proximity analysis and natural-language search for HDB resale insights.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building a LangGraph Multi-Agent System</title>
      <link>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2025/11/building-a-langgraph-multi-agent-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 18:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2025/11/building-a-langgraph-multi-agent-system/</guid>
      <description>This post walks through building a complete multi-agent system using LangGraph—from a simple deterministic chain to a fully orchestrated ReAct agent and a modular supervisor-led MAS. It integrates Postgres (via MCP Toolbox), Tavily web search, and custom Python tools to analyze Singapore HDB resale data and nearby amenities. Complete with diagrams, code walkthroughs, and LangSmith Studio deployment, this guide demonstrates how to design practical, production-ready agent workflows using LangChain and LangGraph.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ADK Web Multi-Agent System</title>
      <link>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2025/11/adk-web-multi-agent-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2025/11/adk-web-multi-agent-system/</guid>
      <description>This blog post details how I built a multi-agent system using Google&amp;rsquo;s ADK, powered by OpenRouter models, for a web application focused on Singapore&amp;rsquo;s HDB data. The system integrates structured data via PostgreSQL (managed by MCP Toolbox) and general statistics via the Data Commons MCP Tools. The architecture uses a Coordinator/Dispatcher pattern to intelligently route HDB-specific queries to the PostgreSQL agent and general queries to the Data Commons agent, ensuring specialized and efficient data retrieval.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI-Driven 3D Workflows with n8n</title>
      <link>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2025/09/ai-driven-3d-workflows-with-n8n/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2025 20:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2025/09/ai-driven-3d-workflows-with-n8n/</guid>
      <description>This post explores how to integrate n8n, OpenRouter, and Blender MCP to create AI-driven 3D modeling workflows. Starting with an AI agent chat in n8n, I bridge prompts to Blender using a custom server, generating a condominium prototype complete with materials, landscaping, and cinematic lighting. Along the way, I highlight practical challenges—like material tuning and lighting setup—and show how automation and AI make complex 3D tasks conversational and modular. The result is a workflow that moves closer to a no-code, AI-powered approach to 3D design.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blender Meets MCP</title>
      <link>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2025/09/blender-meets-mcp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2025 20:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2025/09/blender-meets-mcp/</guid>
      <description>A step-by-step guide to integrating the Model Context Protocol (MCP) with Blender. From setup and server connections to building a datacenter model, discover how AI-driven workflows enhance 3D design and creativity.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Run gpt-oss Locally on Ryzen AI</title>
      <link>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2025/08/run-gpt-oss-locally-on-ryzen-ai/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 20:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2025/08/run-gpt-oss-locally-on-ryzen-ai/</guid>
      <description>Learn how to run OpenAI’s new gpt-oss model locally on a Ryzen AI Max+ 395 mini PC. This guide covers setting up Ollama, Cursor with Kilo Code, and OpenRouter to build a multi-model chat app that queries GPT-3.5, Claude, Mistral, LLaMA, Gemini, and more in parallel. Responses are consolidated into one clean interface—no more juggling multiple tabs. While local gpt-oss runs slower than cloud-hosted models, this experiment shows how anyone can explore AI development locally with modern tools.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Running Bolt.diy with OpenRouter</title>
      <link>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2025/07/running-bolt.diy-with-openrouter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jul 2025 20:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://seehiong.github.io/posts/2025/07/running-bolt.diy-with-openrouter/</guid>
      <description>This post explores running the open-source bolt.diy locally and integrating it with OpenRouter to experiment with various LLMs. I document the development of TextForge—a multi-tool text manipulation app—using one-shot prompts and compare outputs from models like Claude 3 and DeepSeek Chat. The post shares setup steps, performance benchmarks, cost breakdowns, and lessons learned from building a locally hosted, LLM-driven developer tool.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
