<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Multipass on See Hiong&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://seehiong.github.io/tags/multipass/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Multipass on See Hiong&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2024 10:00:00 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://seehiong.github.io/tags/multipass/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Scaling Kafka Workloads with KEDA in Kubernetes</title>
      <link>https://seehiong.github.io/2024/scaling-kafka-workloads-with-keda-in-kubernetes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2024 10:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://seehiong.github.io/2024/scaling-kafka-workloads-with-keda-in-kubernetes/</guid>
      <description>This post demonstrates how to use KEDA, a Kubernetes-based Event Driven Autoscaler, to dynamically scale Kafka consumer workloads. Building on a previous setup with Kafka on MicroK8s, the guide walks through the installation of KEDA, configuring Kafka consumers, setting up secrets for authentication, and creating a ScaledObject to manage scaling based on message load. The post also includes practical examples of scaling under different loads, showcasing how KEDA automates horizontal scaling without requiring changes to the microservices code, making it easier to manage workloads in a Kubernetes environment.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Setting Up Kafka with MicroK8s and Multipass</title>
      <link>https://seehiong.github.io/2024/setting-up-kafka-with-microk8s-and-multipass/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2024 10:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://seehiong.github.io/2024/setting-up-kafka-with-microk8s-and-multipass/</guid>
      <description>My homelab is a playground for experimenting with various tools and setups. However, for Proof of Concept (POC) environments, a lightweight and portable setup is often more suitable. In this post, I will guide you through setting up a MicroK8s environment in a virtual machine using Multipass. This POC demonstrates how Kafka can be set up in this environment.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
